Guide to the Gerald Gunther Ppapers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Gerald Gunther papers
1807-2002
1940-2002
SC0753
Gunther, Gerald, 1927-2002.
140 Linear feet
Collection includes correspondence; Gunther's writings; biographical materials; files from his work on the Constitutional Law casebook; research files on Learned Hand, including photocopies of original documents; and microfilmed records of Supreme Court cases dating back to 1807.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Gerald Gunther, the leading constitutional law scholar in the United States, joined the faculty of the Stanford Law School in 1962 and was the William Nelson Cromwell Professor of Law, Emeritus, at the time of his death in 2002. Born in Germany in 1927, he immigrated to the United States with his family in 1938. He earned his undergraduate degree at Brooklyn College, his master's degree in public law and government at Columbia, and his law degree at Harvard Law School, graduating second in his class in 1953. He was then appointed to a prestigious one year clerkship with Judge Learned Hand of the United States Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit, followed in 1954-1955 by a clerkship with Chief Justice Earl Warren. Highly regarded for his casebook on constitutional law, he also wrote a prize-winning biography of Learned Hand. At Stanford he was known for his passionate defense of freedom of speech on the campus.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes correspondence; Gunther's writings; biographical materials; files from his work on the Constitutional Law casebook; research files on Learned Hand, including photocopies of original documents; and microfilmed records of Supreme Court cases dating back to 1807.
Access Terms
Gunther, Gerald, 1927-2002.; Hand, Learned, 1872-1961.; Stanford University. School of Law--Faculty.; Constitutional law--United States.
Collection Contents
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2004-332
  - Wheaton Notebooks, 1816-1827 (Box 1)
  - WV.P & Related Cases (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (re Wheaton and Wv.P) (Box 1)
  - Hand Research Data – Clark Papers – Miscellaneous interview with clerks, etc. (Box 2)
  - Genealogy; [illeg.] to LH; [illeg.] to children; Financial records (some originals) (Box 3)
  - G. Gunther chron files 1984-1987 (Box 4)
  - Manuscript file Jan.-Dec. 1823 and Jan.-Dec. 1824 [copies of documents] (Box 5)
  - Marshall Court History A – G, H – T, and U – XYZ (Box 6)
  - Case summaries and index – lower Federal Courts 1815-1835 (Box 6)
  - ? Hand biography – early drafts (Box 7)
  - Usingen Corporation (old financial data [1983-85]) (Box 8)
  - Runaway Constitutional Convention Data (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Speeches (including CON-CON) (Box 9)
  - Unigen Retirement Plan Data (Box 9)
  - Marshall Court Material (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous microfilms (Box 10)
  - Clay, Appellate Case Files, Supreme Court (Box 10)
  - [box contains microfilm reels and notecards] (Box 10)
  - Hand Biography – early drafts (Box 11)
  - Supreme Court Argument Notes & Manuscript - Baldwin Notes v. Wheaton v. Peters (Box 12)
  - 9th Edition – adoptions (Box 13)
  - 10th Edition – adoptions (Box 13)
  - 10th Edition Galley Additions (Box 13)
  - 11th Edition (Box 13)
  - Casebook – 11th edition, 1990 supplement (Box 13)
  - Casebook – 11th edition – corrections (Box 13)
  - Con Law – 11th edition – advertising (Box 13)
  - Con Law – 11th edition – reactions (Box 13)
  - Con Law II Course 1988 (Box 13)
  - Con Law II Course 1989 (Box 13)
  - Con Law Casebook – 11th edition – revisions (Box 13)
  - Con Law Casebook – 11th edition – addenda (Box 13)
  - Con Law Workshop Fall 1987 (Box 13)
  - Con Law Workshop 1988 (Box 13)
  - Con Law Workshop 1989 (Box 13)
  - Con Law Workshop 1990 (Box 13)
  - Eleventh (11th ) Edition – Adoptions (Box 13)
  - Individual Rights – 4th edition (Box 13)
  - China – file #1, #2, #3 (Box 14)
  - Foundation Press – 3/86 – 3/87 (Box 14)
  - Personal 1986 (Box 14)
  - Recommendations 1986 (Box 14)
  - Stanford Press Board (Box 14)
  - United Air 1982-86 (Box 14)
  - Books (Learned Hand) 6 copies (Box 15)
  - American Bar Association (Box 16)
  - American Express Travel Card (Box 16)
  - Amex Corp card (Box 16)
  - American Express Corp Card 1993 (Box 16)
  - American Express (Box 16)
  - American Philosophical Society 1989-90 (Box 16)
  - Arizona State University 1994 (Box 16)
  - Atcheson (Box 16)
  - Berkeley Appearnace (Box 16)
  - Anne Bingaman (Box 16)
  - Bingaman – personal (Box 16)
  - Biographer's Seminar (Box 16)
  - Book – corrections (Box 16)
  - Book Travel Expenses 1994 (Box 16)
  - Bookstore readings – LH (Box 16)
  - Brickner (Box 16)
  - Brooklyn Law Review (Box 16)
  - Brooklyn Law School (Box 16)
  - E. Chadbourn (Box 16)
  - D. Cole (Box 16)
  - Columbus, Ohio (Box 16)
  - Detroit Appearance 10/26/94 (Box 16)
  - Door decorations 1993 (Box 16)
  - Duquesne (Box 16)
  - LH: LH – family interview I & II (Box 17)
  - LH: Crosskey Lecture 1976 (Box 17)
  - LH: Henkin (Columbia) interview (Box 17)
  - LH: Hand Genealogy & Family Background (V+) (Box 17)
  - LH: GG Interview 1958 (Box 17)
  - LH: Lippmann – LH correspondence (Box 17)
  - LH: Lippmann – GG interview (Box 17)
  - LH: Henkin – Interview (extra copy & notes) (Box 17)
  - Holmes – Vol. 2 Data (Box 18)
  - Richard Ellis (Box 19)
  - Federal BAR Council – Hand speech (Box 19)
  - 4th Circuit Conference (Box 19)
  - Harvard (Box 19)
  - Harvard Saturday Program (Box 19)
  - Houston (Box 19)
  - Knopf – Paul Schnee (Box 19)
  - L.A. Talk (Box 19)
  - Law Review (Box 19)
  - Lewis & Clark (Box 19)
  - Menlo Park (Box 19)
  - George Martin (Box 19)
  - Linde (Box 19)
  - National Humanities Center (Box 19)
  - New Mexico (Box 19)
  - NYC Bar Assoc (Box 19)
  - NYU Conference (Box 19)
  - Personal, 1994-June 1995 (Box 19)
  - Posner (Box 19)
  - Gunther Miscellaneous files (Box 20)
  - Writings & Clippings, 1980-83 (Box 20)
  - Writings & Clippings, 1984 (Box 20)
  - Writings & Clippings 1985 (Box 20)
  - Writings & Clippings 1986 (Box 20)
  - Writings & Clippings 1987 (Box 20)
  - Casebook materials (Box 20)
  - Con Law – grades & exams (Box 20)
  - Hand Biography Research – misc. files (Box 21)
  - Chapters (Box 21)
  - Addenda (supplemental research) (Box 21)
  - Knopf-Bristol (Box 22)
  - Knopf-Permissions (Box 22)
  - Knopf-Prepublication activities (Box 22)
  - Martin Levin (Hand Publication) (Box 22)
  - NYU Conference (Box 22)
  - Personal 1996-97 (Box 22)
  - Personal 1997 (Box 22)
  - Powell correspondence (Box 22)
  - Recommendations 1996-97 (Box 22)
  - Hand Biography – notes on boxes beyond 100, Xeroxes of Chafee Papers, etc. (Box 23)
  - Hand Biography – Gus Hand (Box 24)
  - More Hough correspondence & misc. research (including Elaine Furey materials) (Box 24)
  - Hand Bio reactions (Box 25)
  - Harvard visiting committee (Box 25)
  - Harvard University Press (Box 25)
  - Israel (Box 25)
  - Knopf – promotions (Box 25)
  - Knopf – Sifton (Box 25)
  - Knopf – Zigman (Box 25)
  - Nathalie Gutenstein (Box 25)
  - Hand biography – early chapters, data, & drafts (Box 26)
  - Hand Research etc. – miscellaneous (Box 27)
  - Hand related notes (Box 27)
  - Pound conference June 1983 (Box 27)
  - Hand Biography – early draft chapters & misc. (Box 28)
  - Hand Biography Research Data including interviews & background data (Box 29)
  - GG – Chron files Jan. 1993-March 1994 (Box 30)
  - Personal 1995 (Box 30)
  - Recommendations 1995-96 (Box 30)
  - Marshall Court history Chapter I-IV-XIII and yellow pages (Box 31)
  - Princeton (Box 32)
  - Recommendation 1992-June 1995 (Box 32)
  - Reily (Box 32)
  - Jeff Rosen (Box 32)
  - Rodell (Box 32)
  - Sacramento (Box 32)
  - San Diego Meeting 6/22/95 (Box 32)
  - Seattle, Washington (Box 32)
  - Soccer (Box 32)
  - Stanford University (Box 32)
  - Strossen (Box 32)
  - Supreme Court Historical Society – Washington, DC 6/95 (Box 32)
  - GG – Writings & Clippings 1991 (Box 32)
  - GG – Writings & Clippings 1992 (Box 32)
  - GG – Writings & Clippings 1993 (Box 32)
  - HOLMES – Admin & Gen (Box 33)
  - Misc CH VIII Osborn & Basic (Box 33)
  - Vol 1 Data (Box 33)
  - Hand Research – Index of Summaries or Misc. Correspondence (Box 34)
  - Papers & Relevant Student Seminar Papers (Box 34)
  - GG – Chron files – Aug-Sept 1994 (Box 35)
  - GG – Chron files – April-June 1994 (Box 35)
  - GG – Chron files – Oct-Dec. 1994 (Box 35)
  - GG – Chron files – Jan-March 1995 (Box 35)
  - GG – Chron files – April-June 1995 (Box 35)
  - GG – Chron files – July-Sept. 1995 (Box 35)
  - GG – Chron files – Oct-Dec 1995 (Box 35)
  - LH Biography – Background Notes and Transcriptions of Correspondence in Box 100 Series (Box 36)
  - Hand Research data – addenda to various draft chapters – [illeg.] on chapters & Manton (Box 37)
  - Hand Research (Box 38)
  - LH to FAH correspondence (Box 38)
  - LH to MHD correspondence (Box 38)
  - Student papers from class taught by Gunther (Box 38B)
  - Hand Biography Research Data (Box 39)
  - Reporters 4/15/15 – 6/18/67; Cases 1928-48; Miscellaneous (Box 40)
  - Chapter drafts (History of Supreme Court/Smith Thompson) (Box 41)
  - Monthly files 1834-1835 (Box 42)
  - 1819 files (Box 43)
  - Possibly course files and/or research files (Box 44)
  - 1828 files; note cards (Box 45)
  - 1829, 1930 files (Box 46)
  - Copies of documents; drafts of a book (Box 47)
  - Copies of documents; drafts of a book (Box 48)
  - Copies of documents re Virginia and T. Jefferson (Box 49)
  - Monthly files 1811-1812 (Box 50)
  - Chapter drafts XI-XV (Box 51)
  - Case Research files (Box 52)
  - Memos for revision; drafts (Box 53)
  - Chapter drafts; binders (Box 54)
  - Excerpts/annotations from James Kent Book (Box 55)
  - Photocopies of historical documents and letters (Box 56)
  - Monthly files 1830-1831 [copies of documents] (Box 57)
  - Attorney General Papers & Bankruptcy Bills (Box 58)
  - Manuscript files Jan. 1825-May 1827 [copies of documents] (Box 59)
  - Manuscript files June 1827-Dec. 1827 [copies of documents] (Box 60)
  - Hand research data – Hough, misc. acquisitions (Box 60)
  - Background research (Box 60)
  - Foundation Board (1997 meeting) (Box 61)
  - Leslie Allison (Box 61)
  - LH Binder (Learned Hand: The Man and the Judge) chaps. I-IX (corrected copy) (Box 61)
  - LH Binder (Learned Hand: The Man and the Judge) chaps. X-XV (corrected copy) (Box 61)
  - LH Book Appearances (Box 61)
  - Hand Biography – Research Drafts (Box 62)
  - Powell Correspondence (Box 63)
  - Recommendations 1989 (Box 63)
  - Rehnquist – Scalia (Box 63)
  - Salzburg Seminar 1989 (Box 63)
  - Stanford 1988-89 (2 folders) (Box 63)
  - Stanford benefits (3 folders) (Box 63)
  - Stanford Curriculum (Box 63)
  - Steel, Ronald (Box 63)
  - Stevens Correspondence (Box 63)
  - Supreme Court Hist. Soc. Yearbook through 1989 (Box 63)
  - Tarlock – ALI (Box 63)
  - Appellate Cases of the Supreme Court 1807-1829 (36 reels of microfilm) (Box 64)
  - Misc. monthly files 1832 and 1829 (Box 65)
  - 1 card file box and 2 folders with reports from House and Senate judiciary committees (Box 66)
  - Research Data re Cherokees & state of Georgia (Box 67)
  - Research Data re Cherokees & state of Georgia (Box 68)
  - Personal 1962-64 (Box 69)
  - Cromwell Project 1957-60 (Box 69)
  - Dowling 7th edition (Box 69)
  - GG – Financial (Box 69)
  - GG – Recommendations (Box 69)
  - GG – Book Reviews (Box 69)
  - GG – Supreme Court Speech 1964 (Box 69)
  - Stanford – President Sterling (Box 69)
  - GG – personal 1965 (Box 69)
  - Federal Courts – S. Shultz. Class notes, Spring 1971 (Box 69)
  - GG – Claremont Men's College (Prof. Winston M. Fisk) (Box 69)
  - GG – personal 1966 (Box 69)
  - GG – Hughes Lecture (Box 69)
  - Misc. monthly files 1816 and 1817 (Box 70)
  - Legislative History Materials and Index to Materials (Box 71)
  - Appellate cases of SCOTUS (49 reels of microfilm) (Box 72)
  - Chron Files, 2002 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Chron Files, 2001 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - Chron Files, 2000 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Chron Files, Jan.-March 1999 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Chron Files, 1999 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Chron Files, October-Dec. 1998 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Chron Files, July-September 1998 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - Chron Files, April-June 1998 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - Chron Files, Jan.-March 1998 (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - Chron Files, October-Dec. 1997 (Box 73, Folder 10)
  - Chron Files, July-September 1997 (Box 73, Folder 11)
  - Chron Files, April-June 1997 (Box 73, Folder 12)
  - Chron Files, Jan.-March 1997 (Box 73, Folder 13)
  - Barbara Gunther, Oct 2000 (Box 73, Folder 14)
  - January 1820 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - February 1820 (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - March 1820 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - April 1820 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - May 1820 (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - June 1820 (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - July 1820 (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - August 1820 (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - September 1820 (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - October 1820 (Box 74, Folder 10)
  - November 1820 (Box 74, Folder 11)
  - December 1820 (Box 74, Folder 12)
  - January 1821 (Box 74, Folder 13)
  - February 1821 (Box 74, Folder 14)
  - March 1821 (Box 74, Folder 15)
  - April 1821 (Box 74, Folder 16)
  - May 1821 (Box 74, Folder 17)
  - June 1821 (Box 74, Folder 18)
  - July 1821 (Box 74, Folder 19)
  - August 1821 (Box 74, Folder 20)
  - September 1821 (Box 74, Folder 21)
  - October 1821 (Box 74, Folder 22)
  - November 1821 (Box 74, Folder 23)
  - December 1821 (Box 74, Folder 24)
  - January 1822 (Box 74, Folder 25)
  - February 1822 (Box 74, Folder 26)
  - March 1822 (Box 74, Folder 27)
  - April 1822 (Box 74, Folder 28)
  - May 1822 (Box 74, Folder 29)
  - June 1822 (Box 74, Folder 30)
  - July 1822 (Box 74, Folder 31)
  - September 1822 (Box 74, Folder 32)
  - October 1822 (Box 74, Folder 33)
  - November 1822 (Box 74, Folder 34)
  - December 1822 (Box 74, Folder 35)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2008-048
  - AAAS 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AALS (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ACLU (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ACLU – Baldwin Award Committee (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Air Travel Complaints (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - AJC (American Jewish Committee) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - ALI – 1989- (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - ALLISON, Leslie Minturn (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Philosophical Society (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Philosophical Society (Part 2) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Philosophical Society (Part 3) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The American Scholar Magazine (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Arizona State University Symposium (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Australia (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Baier (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Lisa Beattie (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Behavioral Sciences Center (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - GG – Benefits (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Borders – Book Appearance (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Book – Awards (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Book – Sales Figures (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Book Talk (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Brooklyn Law School (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Hannah Cahn (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Cardozo – Seminar (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Gerhard Casper (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Jonathan Churchill (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - CIIS (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Clinton (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - COIF (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - COIF Award (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Colorado (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Colorado 9/95 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Computer (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Archie Cox (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - DC Circuit Speech (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Delta Dental (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Dentists (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Dimock (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Murray Dry (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Duquesne (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - England (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - GG – Estate (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Faculty Club (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Anne Fadiman (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - GG – Financial – Endowed Account (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Florida (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Foundation Press Board (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Foundation Press Board (Part 2) (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Foundation Press Book Contract (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Germany Et Al (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Germany (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Germany (Folder 2) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Germany (Folder 3) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Paul Ginsberg (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Judge Ruth Bader Ginsburg (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Andrew Gunther (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Barbara Gunther (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Dan Gunther (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Herbert Gutenstein (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Peter Gutenstein (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Hand – Book Talk (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Hand Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Hand Papers Shipment (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Illustrations for Hand Biography (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Hand Photographs (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Hand – Phyllis Kern (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Hand – Selected Lectures (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Harvard Law School Reunion (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Harvard Visiting Committee (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Hawaii Law Review (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Hildegard (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - GG – House (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Houston (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Humanities Seminar (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Chris Hunt (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Ireland (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Ireland 2002 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Israel (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Japan (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Constance Jordan (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Judiciary Project – 20th Century Fund (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 20th Century Fund – Citizens for Independent Courts (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Jury Duty ‘95 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Kambe (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - GG – Keogh Plan (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Knight Journalism Fellowships – 2002 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Knopf – Book Contract (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Knopf – 1989 Contract (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Kolb (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Knopf (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Lahav (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Pnina Lahav (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Letters I (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Letters II (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Letters III (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Letters IV (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - From Reactions + Blurbs (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Letters V (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - GG – Personal – TE-RL-GG Docs (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Personal – Old Judicial Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - GG – Photos (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Photos (Folder 2) (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Pirie (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Powell – Supreme Court Memorial (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Provost's Account (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Quinlan (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Rabban (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Recommendations 2000 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Stanford Retirement (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Retirement (Folder 2) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Retirement (Folder 3) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Retirement – Med. Insurance (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Reviews I (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Reviews II (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Reviews III (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Reviews IV (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Reviews V (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Reviews V (Folder 2) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Reviews V (Folder 3) (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Reviews V (Folder 4) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Reviews – Selections (Master Files) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Safe Deposit Box (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Schurtman (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Scott, Kenneth E. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Smith Barney (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Soccer (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - D. Souter (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - South America (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Spinner (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Stanford (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Stanford (Folder 2) (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Stanford (Folder 3) (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Stanford Benefits – '95 Coverage (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Benefits – 1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Benefits – Retirement Option Changes ‘83 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Early Retirement Plan (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Faculty Club (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Stanford – Financial Rats Account (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Stanford – Fundraising (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Law (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Law School – Rats Account (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Stanford – Library Associates (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Stanford Press Contacts (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Stanford Retirement (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Stanford Supplemental Medical Insurance – Blue Shield (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Stanford Travel (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Annelin Starke (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - State Bar, CA (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Richard Stern (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Strossen (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Subscriptions (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - K. Sullivan (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Supreme Court Historical Society (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Supreme Court Panel, Oct. 14 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Switzerland (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Tarlock (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Tatel (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - File Thirteen (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Travel (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Travel Agency (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - UCLA (Karst) (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - UCLA Law Review (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - U.S. Assn. of Constitutional Law (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Gerald Gunther – Vitae (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Bio Updated 1/99 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Liza Weiman (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - James Weinstein (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Westlaw (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Witkin Foundation (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Witkin Medical Committee (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Writings and Clippings ‘96 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Papers & Clippings ‘96 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - GG – Writings & Clippings ‘95 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - GG – Writings & Clippings ‘94 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Zimmerman (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Grandfather Election (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Usingen Audit (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Usingen Audit (Folder 2) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - GG – Valuables List (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - GG – Wallet ID Cards not taken on trip 6/76 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Usingen Corporation (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Usingen – Pension Plan ‘87 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - “LH” (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Casebook – 13th Edition (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Casebook – Contract (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Gunther – Remembered (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Constitutional Law I – A – 1 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Constitutional Law I – A – 1 (Folder 2) (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Stanford Speech (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - No title (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Stanford Speech II7 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Untitled (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Untitled (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - VI-2 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - VI-2 (2) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - VI – 3 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - VI – 3 (2) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Stanford/Marshall (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Various Books (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Albany-Kent Volume 1 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 7/64 Columbia Spec. Coll. Press (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Misc News (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Chapter IV (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - McCulloch v. Md. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - McCulloch, JM Reply (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Roane – 1821 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Roane – Biogs (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Roane Copy (?) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Marshall Era SC (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Various Articles (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Mildred Minturn (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Supreme Court Seminar (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Unlabeled (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - 2 Floppy Disk boxes, 2 binders, box of film and various publications (Box 8)
  - Various publications by other authors, ephemera, film, cassettes, and VHS tapes (Box 9)
  - Various films, pocket constitutions (Box 10)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2009-223
  - C-LH - Acheson, 1971-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - GG-LH - D. Nelson Adams, 1964-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Includes transcript of GG and Adams interview, 1970; copy of Adams' "Some Recollections ofMy Year with Judge Learned Hand, 1935-1936."
  - GG-LH Aidinoff, M. Bernard, Esq., 1959-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Includes transcript of GG and Aidinoff interview, 1970; list of Hand's law clerks.
  - Albany Law School, 1902-1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - C-LH Albany Academy, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Allan, F. Aley (LH Clerk), 1945-1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Includes transcript of GG and Aley interview, 1971.
  - C-LH American Law Institute, 1980-1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - C-LH Antitrust, 1986-1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)